So, I am indeed going to talk about
إذا فأنا بالتأكيد سوف أتحدث عن
the spaces men create for themselves,
الفسحات التي يصنعها الرجال لأنفسهم.
but first I want to tell you why I'm here.
ولكنني أولا أريد أن أخبركم عن سبب وجودي هنا.
I'm here for two reasons. These two guys
أنا هنا لسببين: هذان الشخصان
are my two sons Ford and Wren.
هما أولادي٬ "فورد" و"ورين".
When Ford was about three years old,
عندما كان "فورد" في الثالثة من عمره تقريبا
we shared a very small room together,
تشاركنا غرفة صغيرة جدا مع بعضنا٬
in a very small space.
وفي مساحة صغيرة جدا.
My office was on one half of the bedroom,
كان مكتبي عبارة عن نصف غرفة النوم
and his bedroom was on the other half.
وكانت غرفة نومه هي النصف الاخر.
And you can imagine, if you're a writer,
ويمكنكم أن تتصوروا كيف سيكون هذا لكاتب
that things would get really crowded around deadlines.
وكيف ستصبح الأمور شديدة الإزدحام في أوقات مواعيد التسليم.
So when Wren was on the way,
لذا عندما اقتربت ولادة "ورين"
I realized I needed to find a space of my own.
أدركت أنني بحاجة إلى فسحتي الخاصة.
There was no more space in the house. So I went out to the backyard,
لم تتوفر المساحة داخل البيت فخرجت إلى الباحة الخلفية٬
and without any previous building experience,
ودون أي خبرة في مجال البناء
and about 3,000 dollars and some
وحوالي 3000 الٱف دولار وبعض
recycled materials, I built this space.
المواد المصنّعة٬ قمت ببناء هذه الفسحة.
It had everything I needed. It was quiet.
كانت تشتمل على كل شيء احتجته: كانت هادئة
There was enough space. And I had control, which was very important.
وكانت مساحة كافية٬ وكانت لي السيطرة٬ وهذا مهم جدا.
As I was building this space, I thought
وعندما كنت أبني الفسحة ظننت
to myself, "Surely I'm not the only guy
"بالتأكيد لست أنا أول رجل
to have to have carved out a space for his own."
صنع لنفسه فسحة خاصة."
So I did some research.
لذا قمت ببعض الأبحاث
And I found that there was an historic precedence.
ووجدت أن هناك أسبقية لهذا العمل.
Hemingway had his writing space.
كان لدى "هيمينغواي" فسحته الخاصة للكتابة
Elvis had two or three manspaces,
وكان لدى "إلفيس" فسحتين أو ثلاث٬
which is pretty unique because he lived with both his wife and his mother in Graceland.
وهذا شيء فريد من نوعه لأنه كان يعيش مع زوجته وأمه في "غرايس لاند".
In the popular culture, Superman had the Fortress of Solitude,
في الثقافة الشعبية٬ كان ل"سوبرمان" "حصن الوحدة"
and there was, of course, the Batcave.
وطبعا لديك "مغارة رجل الوطواط".
So I realized then that I wanted to go out on a journey
لذا أدركت حينها أنني أردت الخروج في رحلة
and see what guys were creating for themselves now.
لرؤية ما يصنعه الرجال لأنفسهم.
Here is one of the first spaces I found. It is in Austin, Texas,
هذه إحدى أول الفسحات التي وجدتها٬ وهي موجودة في "أوستين" في ولاية تكساس٬
which is where I'm from.
والتي أنا منها.
On the outside it looks like a very typical garage, a nice garage.
في الخارج تبدو كأي كاراج اخر٬ كاراج جيد.
But on the inside, it's anything but.
ولكن في الداخل٬ هي شيء مختلف تماما.
And this, to me, is a pretty classic manspace.
وهذه بالنسبة لي٬ فسحة رجال تقليدية.
It has neon concert posters, a bar
فيها ملصقات نيون لحفلات الموسيقى٬ مِشرب٬
and, of course, the leg lamp,
وطبعا مصباح الرِجل٬
which is very important.
الذي هو مهم جدا.
I soon realized that manspaces didn't have to be only inside.
وسرعان ما أدركت أن فسحات الرجال لا تقتصر على كونها في الداخل فقط.
This guy built a bowling alley in his backyard,
هذا الرجل بنى ممر للبولينغ في باحته الخلفية
out of landscaping timbers, astroturf.
من أخشاب البرية٬ "أستروتورف"
And he found the scoreboard in the trash.
ووجد لوحة تسجيل النقاط في القمامة.
Here's another outdoor space, a little bit more sophisticated.
هذه فسحة خارجية أخرى أكثر تعقيدا.
This a 1923 wooden tugboat,
هذا زورق سحب خشبي من سنة 1923
made completely out of Douglas fir.
مصنوع بالكامل من خشب تنّور "دوغلاس".
The guy did it all himself.
صنعه الرجل لوحده.
And there is about 1,000 square feet of hanging-out space inside.
وهناك حوالي ال1000 قدم مربع من المساحة في الداخل.
So, pretty early on in my investigations
لذا أدركت باكرا في تحقيقاتي
I realized what I was finding was not what I expected to find,
أن الذي كنت أجده لم يكن ما توقعت إيجاده
which was, quite frankly, a lot of beer can pyramids
والذي تخيلت أن يكون هرما مصنوعا من علب البيرة
and overstuffed couches and flat-screen TVs.
وأرائك ضخمة وشاشات مسطحة.
There were definitely hang-out spots.
بالتأكيد كانت هناك فسحات للتسلية٬
But some were for working, some were for playing,
ولكن بعضها كانت للعمل وبعضها كانت للّعب
some were for guys to collect their things.
وبعضها كانت لرجال يجمعّون الأغراض.
Most of all, I was just surprised with what I was finding.
بشكل عام٬ كنت أُفاجئ بما أجده.
Take this place for example.
خذوا هذا المكان مثلا.
On the outside it looks like a typical northeastern garage.
في الخارج يبدو كأي كاراج تقليدي في شمال شرقي أميركا.
This is in Long Island, New York.
هذا في "لونغ أيلند" في نيويورك.
The only thing that might tip you off is the round window.
الشيء الوحيد الغريب هو الشباك الدائري.
On the inside it's a recreation of a
في الداخل هو إعادة تصميم
16th century Japanese tea house.
لبيت شاي ياباني من القرن السادس عشر.
The man imported all the materials from Japan,
قام الرجل بإستيراد جميع المواد من اليابان
and he hired a Japanese carpenter
واستخدم نجارا يابانيا
to build it in the traditional style.
لبنائه على الطريقة التقليدية.
It has no nails or screws.
لا يحتوي على المسامير والبراغي٬
All the joints are hand-carved and hand-scribed.
وجميع المفاصل منحوتة ومكتوبة باليد.
Here is another pretty typical scene. This is a suburban Las Vegas neighborhood.
هذا مشهد تقليدي اخر. هذا حي سكني في لاس فيغاس٬
But you open one of the garage doors
ولكنك عندما تفتح بوابة الكاراج
and there is a professional-size boxing ring inside.
تجد حلبة ملاكمة محترفة في الداخل.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And so there is a good reason for this.
لذا فهناك سبب جيد لهذا.
It was built by this man who is Wayne McCullough.
صنعها هذا الرجل٬ "واين مككوللو".
He won the silver medal for Ireland
ربح الميدالية الفضية لإيرلندا
in the 1992 Olympics,
في أوليمبياد ال1992
and he trains in this space. He trains other people.
وهو يتمرن في هذه الفسحة ويمرن الاخرين.
And right off the garage he has his own trophy room
وبجوار الكاراج لديه غرفة الجوائز خاصته
where he can sort of bask in his accomplishments,
حيث يقوم بالاستمتاع بإنجازاته٬
which is another sort of important part about a manspace.
الذي هو جزء اخر مهم في فسحات الرجال.
So, while this space represents someone's profession,
بينما تمثل هذه الفسحة مهنة الشخص٬
this one certainly represents a passion.
هذه تمثل شغف الشخص لشيء.
It's made to look like the inside of an English sailing ship.
صنعها لتبدو كداخل سفينة إبحار إنجليزية.
It's a collection of nautical antiques from the 1700s and 1800s.
هذه مجموعة من التحف البحرية من القرن الثامن والتاسع عشر
Museum quality.
ونوعيتها نوعية القطع في المتاحف.
So, as I came to the end of my journey,
ومع نهاية رحلتي
I found over 50 spaces.
كنت قد وجدت أكثر من 50 فسحة.
And they were unexpected and they were surprising.
وكانت غير متوقعة ومُفاجئة
But they were also --
ولكنها أيضا كانت --
I was really impressed by how personalized they were,
أعجبت بكم كانت هذه الفسحات شخصية
and how much work went into them.
وبكمية العمل الذي تطلّبوه.
And I realized that's because the guys that I met
وأدركت أن سبب هذا هو أن الرجال الذين التقيت بهم
were all very passionate about what they did.
شديدي الشغف لما صنعوه
And they really loved their professions.
وأنهم يحبون مهنهم كثيرا
And they were very passionate about their collections and their hobbies.
وأنهم شغوفين جدا بمجموعاتهم وهواياتهم.
And so they created these spaces
لذا صنعوا هذه الفسحات
to reflect what they love to do,
ليعكسوا ما يحبون فعله
and who they were.
وليعكسوا هوياتهم.
So if you don't have a space of your own,
لذا لو لم يكن لديك فسحتك الخاصة٬
I highly recommend finding one, and getting into it.
فأنا أنصحكم بإيجادها والإنتقال إليها.
Thank you very much.
شكرا جزيلا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)